Guide to the John McComb Architectural Drawings Collection 1766-1829 PR 40
New-York Historical Society
- [Chinoiserie, attributed; fireplace with frame] (Box McComb Box 13, Item 223)
- Church steeple (Box McComb box 4, Item 64)
- Church steeple (Box McComb box 4, Item 65)
- Church steeple (attrib.) Brick Presbyterian (attrib.), [1823-1825] (Box McComb box 4, Item 069 recto)
- Church steeple, unidentified Ink, LR: "Design of a Steeple for"; other parts erased (Box McComb box 4, Item 68)
- Church steeple, unidentified (Box McComb box 3, Item 47)
- Church steeple, unidentified (Box McComb box 4, Item 66)
- Church, pulpit, unidentifed (Box McComb box 4, Item 60)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 15, Item 262)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb box 3, Item 48)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 15, Item 264)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 10, Item 179)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 19, Item 393)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 8, Item 131)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb box 4, Item 63)
- Church, unidentified ink, UC: "Side View" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 229)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 231)
- Church, unidentified, "Mch 15/05": pencil, LR (Box McComb Box 14, Item 230)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb box 4, Item 071a recto)
- Church, unidentified graphite, LL: "Pulpit" (Box McComb Box 9, Item 143)
- Church, unidentified Two sections looking toward pulpit [attrib.] (Box McComb Box 9, Item 141)
- Church, unidentified Two sections looking toward pulpit (Box McComb Box 9, Item 142)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb box 2, Item 41)
- Church, unidentified List of dimensions: attributed (Box McComb Box 15, Item 261)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb Box 8, Item 132)
- Church, unidentified (Box McComb box 3, Item 49)
- [Church, unidentified] (Box McComb Box 13, Item 222)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] (Box McComb Box 10, Item 172)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] ink, UL-UC: "St. Marys Church Lincoln"; ink, LC: "York Cath.l" (Box McComb Box 10, Item 173)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] (Box McComb Box 10, Item 178)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] ink, UR-UC:"Rough Calculation for Piers at N. River" (Box McComb Box 10, Item 174 recto)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] (Box McComb Box 10, Item 171)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] (Box McComb Box 10, Item 170)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] [Wall St. Presbyterian], 1823; April 3 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 177)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic] central plan (Box McComb Box 10, Item 175)
- Church, unidentified [Gothic], [Wall St. Presbyterian?], 1823; March 31 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 176)
- Church, unidentified. Brick Presbyterian Church alteration [attrib], [1822 - 1823] (Box McComb box 2, Item 040a)
- Church, unidentified. Brick Presbyterian Church alteration [attrib], [1822 - 1823] (Box McComb box 2, Item 042b)
- Church, unidentified. Brick Presbyterian Church alteration, attrib., [1822 - 1823] (Box McComb box 2, Item 042a)
- Church, unidentified. Brick Presbytrian Church alteration [attrib], [1822 - 1823]. (Box McComb box 2, Item 040b)
- Church, unidentified. North Dutch [attrib] (Box McComb box 3, Item 45)
- Church, unidentified. North Dutch [attrib] (Box McComb box 3, Item 46)
- Church, unidentified; circular plan [aka central plan auditorium and arena plan.], [1811] (Box McComb box 3, Item 44)
- Circular building elevation, attributed A domed building with Pediment and columns (Cf. Pantheon): attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 340)
- Circular building plan (Box McComb Box 9, Item 150)
- Circular building plan, attributed Plan of a circular church with columed porticoes on four sides: attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 341)
- City Hall City Hall: attributed, [1802-1811] (Box McComb Box 12, Item 200)
- City Hall Grand stairway: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH066)
- City Hall Grand Stairway: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH065)
- City Hall Front Elevation: attrib., 1802 (Box Drawer 15, Item CH001)
- City Hall Urns in niches sketch: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH065 verso)
- City Hall Plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH066 verso)
- City Hall Wall section: attrib., 1804 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH050 1/2)
- City Hall "as Executed": ink, LC Roof Trusses: attrib., 1804 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH050)
- City Hall Volutes, 1803 (Box Drawer 25, Item CH097A verso)
- City Hall "Console for 2"d Order at Full Size": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH085 1/2)
- City Hall "First idea for the Cupola of City Hall}": ink, ML, 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH055 1/2)
- City Hall "Sketch of Finish round udges Seat in Mayors Court Room": pencil, LC, 1810 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH074)
- City Hall "Entablature in Common Council Chamber": pencil, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH072)
- City Hall "Judges Table": pencil, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH073)
- City Hall Sketches for soffit of dome, 1804 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH069 1/2)
- City Hall "Moulding for Tablet on South Front 1/2 Size": ink, LR or Partial Elevation - South Front: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH045)
- City Hall "Cornice at the foot of the Cove": ink, LL-LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH071)
- City Hall "Elevation of One half the Gallery Stretched out": pencil, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH063)
- City Hall "This by ESW used by him on his residence": pencil, LC-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH061 verso)
- City Hall Roof Structure: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH423)
- City Hall "Jno Moore No 14 Rose St.-": ink, UR, 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH088 verso)
- City Hall "Entablature for Mayors Court Room": ink, UR-MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH084)
- City Hall "Entablature in Large Court Room 2'-6"-": ink, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH085)
- City Hall "whole width of Soffit between Col. of Portico": pencil, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH062 verso)
- City Hall A door with transom: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH082 1/2)
- City Hall Court Room: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH077)
- City Hall Section from Rotunda to Exterior: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH083)
- City Hall Capital - interior vestibule: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH061)
- City Hall "2"d Order of New City Hall": partial title, ink, ML, [1803] (Box Drawer 12, Item CH041)
- City Hall Designs for Iron Railings: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH094)
- City Hall Marble Flooring - scale given, 1805 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH070)
- City Hall Circular corridor plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH064 1/2)
- City Hall Sketches: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH055 3/4 verso)
- City Hall Interior Vestibule: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH062)
- City Hall Lesser Stairway Section: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH081)
- City Hall Grand Stairway: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH064)
- City Hall "Section of Common Council Chambers": pencil, UL-UC, 1804 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH080)
- City Hall Grand Stair: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH105)
- City Hall Court Room with Judge's Canopy: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH079)
- City Hall "For the Arms of the United States. For the Arms of the State of New York.": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH095)
- City Hall Grand Stair Detail and Column Detail: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH105 verso)
- City Hall Designs for Iron Railings: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH093)
- City Hall Court Room: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH075)
- City Hall "Cornices only of City Hall": ink, UL, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH084 verso)
- City Hall Section through Grand Stairway, Gallery Dome and Cupola: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH067)
- City Hall Showing entrance of floor beams and sleepers: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH082)
- City Hall "Plan of Attic Story": pencil, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 20, Item CH049)
- City Hall "Entablature for Inside of Colonnade":, 1803 (Box Drawer 18, Item CH025 1/2)
- City Hall "Elevation of One half the North. Front. Basement.": ink, LC-LR, 1804 (Box Drawer 16, Item CH010)
- City Hall "Capitals for 2.d Order of Pilasters for New City Hall": ink, ML, 1804 (Box Drawer 19, Item CH043)
- City Hall "Ionic Base at Large": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH019 1/2)
- City Hall "section Lenghtways of a part of Colonnade": ink, ML-MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 18, Item CH024)
- City Hall Plan and Entablature of Colonnade: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 18, Item CH025)
- City Hall Partial Plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH381 verso)
- City Hall Elevation [vestibule]: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH030 verso)
- City Hall Plan of Second Floor: attrib., 1804 (Box Drawer 8, Item CH015)
- City Hall Roof Plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 17, Item CH018)
- City Hall Partial Front Elevation with Clock: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 20, Item CH046)
- City Hall Main Floor Plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 17, Item CH013)
- City Hall Ionic base, column, capital, entablature of First Order: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH019)
- City Hall North-South Section through Center of City Hall: attrib., 1802 (Box Drawer 15, Item CH003)
- City Hall Elevation Base of Cupola: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH056)
- City Hall "Base for Vestibule": ink, LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH028 1/2)
- City Hall "SENECA Il Filosofo": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 25, Item CH096)
- City Hall "over Grand Stairs City Hall": pencil, MC-LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH053 1/2)
- City Hall Rear Elevation, 1802 (Box Drawer 15, Item CH002)
- City Hall Column or entablature detail: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH029 verso)
- City Hall "the Tower will be Seen from the Park as it is drawn": ink, UC, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH386)
- City Hall Design of the Cupola as executed: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH056 1/2 verso)
- City Hall Designs for statuary, shown on drawings but not executed, 1803 (Box Drawer 25, Item CH098)
- City Hall "West Projection of South Front": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 16, Item CH007)
- City Hall Designs for Statuary shown on drawings but not executed, 1803 (Box Drawer 25, Item CH097A)
- City Hall Urn: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 21, Item CH054)
- City Hall "Ornaments executed on the chimney pieces in the Common Council Chamber City Hall-": ink, UL-UR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH080 1/2)
- City Hall "Park - contains upwards of 4 acres-": ink, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH089)
- City Hall Same. Another view. Justice - rear view., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH059)
- City Hall Design, statuary for Cupola base, south front: attrib., 1805 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH051)
- City Hall Figure Surmounting Cupola, as executed., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH058)
- City Hall "Plan of the First Floor": pencil, LC, 1804 (Box Drawer 17, Item CH014)
- City Hall Cupola: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH391)
- City Hall "Balusters for New City Hall": ink, ML-MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH038)
- City Hall Interior elevations: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH056 verso)
- City Hall "Entrance to the principal Stairs": ink, UL, 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH068)
- City Hall Base of Cupola: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH048 1/2)
- City Hall Working drawing of console used by stone cutters: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH032)
- City Hall Attic front w/moulding for panels: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH047)
- City Hall "Entablature of 2.d Order at Half Size-": ink, MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 18, Item CH035)
- City Hall Windows elevation: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH027)
- City Hall "Architrave of 2"d Order at full Size-": ink, LL, 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH036 1/2)
- City Hall Sketch - Attic Front: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH048)
- City Hall Another Cornice, 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH087 1/2)
- City Hall Window and Door transoms: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH079 1/2)
- City Hall "Baluster for Pedestal of 2"d Order at full Size" w/ seraph: ink, MC-MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH039 1/2)
- City Hall Sketch of detail: attrib. [Console/bracket], 1803 (Box Drawer 21, Item CH052 verso)
- City Hall Elevation: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH388)
- City Hall "Plan of the Cupola for New City Hall": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH055)
- City Hall "Cornice for 2"d Order": ink, LC-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH036)
- City Hall "17 3/4"- for Columns, at Top": pencil, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH021)
- City Hall "Basement Story": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 8, Item CH012)
- City Hall Colonnade balustrade: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH026)
- City Hall "Console for Vestibule": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH028)
- City Hall "Console at half Size": ink, LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH030)
- City Hall Some of floor timbering of second floor: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH017)
- City Hall "Dentils were left out in Execution. " " added in 1"st order - Ionic E.S. Wilde,": pencil, UL, [1803] (Box Drawer 11, Item CH034)
- City Hall Urns: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 21, Item CH054 verso)
- City Hall "Capital for Vestibule City Hall-": ink, LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH020)
- City Hall Details: attrib., 1804 (Box Drawer 20, Item CH046 1/2)
- City Hall Entablature First Order: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH022)
- City Hall "Cornice of the first order at full size": ink, MC-MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH022 1/2)
- City Hall "Archivolt of the first order For New City Hall": ink, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH023 1/2)
- City Hall "Impost of the first order for New City Hall": ink, UC-UR, 1803 (Box Drawer 9, Item CH023)
- City Hall Sketch - Elevation of Cupola: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 22, Item CH055 3/4)
- City Hall "Base and Cap for Pedestal at full Size for the 2d Order-": ink, ML-MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH039)
- City Hall "Rear Front": ink, MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 18, Item CH031)
- City Hall Entablature details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH106)
- City Hall "Half the Center Arch of South Front 3'-3 1/2"-": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 10, Item CH029)
- City Hall Section Grand Stair and Gallery: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH378)
- City Hall "Elevation of One half the Gallery Stretched out": pencil, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item ch063)
- City Hall "West Front": pencil, LC, 1804 (Box Drawer 16, Item CH009)
- City Hall Elevation: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH388 verso)
- City Hall Fence with gate and piers: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH376)
- City Hall Window design: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH352)
- City Hall "Elevation of West Front": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 16, Item CH008)
- City Hall A Cornice, Second Order: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH086)
- City Hall "design for a Lewis at half Size": ink, UL-UC, 1803 (Box Drawer 11, Item CH033)
- City Hall Showing timbering Second Order: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH087)
- City Hall Statuary: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH354)
- City Hall "North Front": pencil, LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 20, Item CH049 1/2)
- City Hall "Supreme Court Room": pencil, LL-LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH385)
- City Hall Exterior? Details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH325)
- City Hall Court Room: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH107)
- City Hall "Ionic Impost full Sise": ink, ML-MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH104)
- City Hall Volute and acanthus leaf details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH047 verso)
- City Hall 3 Lamppost designs: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH374)
- City Hall "Myrtle Branch": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH402)
- City Hall "Lorel Branch": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH403)
- City Hall Reflected Ceiling Plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH078)
- City Hall "Olive Branch": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH400)
- City Hall Doorway details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH368)
- City Hall Doorway details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH383 1/2)
- City Hall Court Room Schemes: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH104 verso)
- City Hall Urns: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH332)
- City Hall Sketches: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH107 verso)
- City Hall Interior Elevation: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH404)
- City Hall Gallery plan: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH378 verso)
- City Hall Doorway details: attrib., 1804 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH384 verso)
- City Hall Partial Elevation of Attic and Base of Cupola: attrib. (Box McComb Drawer 13, Item CH498)
- City Hall Landscape of Island and Lighthouse, [1803] (Box Drawer 12, Item CH055 verso)
- City Hall Court Room: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH076)
- City Hall "Mouldings for Architrave & Pilaster of door in Supreme Court.": ink, MR-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 13, Item CH072 1/2)
- City Hall "Impost for 2d Order": ink, UL, 1803 (Box Drawer 12, Item CH044)
- City Hall Entablature details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH106 verso)
- City Hall Map of City Hall Park: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH088)
- City Hall "Mouldings for Center of Ceiling Common Council Chamber": ink, LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH328)
- City Hall Fence with gate and piers: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH375)
- City Hall "Equal to the projection in the rear of City Hall": pencil, ML-MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH371)
- City Hall Lamppost design: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH372)
- City Hall Grand Stair Scheme: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH329)
- City Hall Grand Stair Details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH329 verso)
- City Hall Well executed detail of stairway, 1804 (Box Drawer 24, Item CH069)
- City Hall Gate and fence: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH373)
- City Hall "Middle door of Chancery Court": pencil, ML-MC, 1804 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH384)
- City Hall Sketch of Dome: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 21, Item CH053)
- City Hall Sketches - Capitals 2nd Order: attrib., 1804 (Box Drawer 18, Item CH037)
- City Hall Sketch of Cupola with Columns: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 21, Item CH052)
- City Hall Details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH390 verso)
- City Hall "Section from East to West of Basement Story through CD": ink, MC, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH390)
- City Hall "BASEMENT STORY": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 8, Item CH011)
- City Hall Details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH385 verso)
- City Hall "Capital for the 2"d Order of Pilasters for New City Hall": ink, LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 19, Item CH040)
- City Hall Base Plan of Cupola: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH089 verso)
- City Hall "Design for the Piers at the lower end of the Park": ink, LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 25, Item CH090)
- City Hall "Railing in Common Council Chamber": ink, MC-MR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH091)
- City Hall 2 doorway designs: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH383)
- City Hall "Ivy Branch": ink, LL-LR, 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH401)
- City Hall "Porters Lodge Lobby": pencil, LL, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH370)
- City Hall "Survey of Dr Osborns 2 Story T. Ho": pencil, UL-UR, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH368 verso)
- City Hall Plan of Second Floor: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 8, Item CH016)
- City Hall Entryway designs: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 14, Item CH097)
- City Hall Balustrade, [1803] (Box Drawer 22, Item CH053 1/2)
- City Hall Doorways (2) and details: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH381)
- City Hall "Capital for 3/4 Columns- 2"d Order": ink, ML, [1803] (Box Drawer 12, Item CH042)
- City Hall Vestibule and Portico: attrib., 1803 (Box Drawer 23, Item CH060)
- City Hall Park Railings, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH092)
- City Hall "Working Drawings of Fence as executed at City Hall Park about the year-": pencil, LL-LC, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH108)
- City Hall Working Drawing of Cupola - as executed., 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item CH057)
- City Hall Park Plan ink, ML: "Plan shewing the situation of the Public Buildings near the East Wing of the New York Institution" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 233)
- City Hall Records McComb Letter regarding marble for City Hall: attrib., 1803; October 11 (Box McComb Box 22)
- City Hall Records John McComb Account Ledger for City Hall: attrib., 1812 (Box McComb Box 22)
- City Hall Records McComb Letter regarding a gold piece: attrib., 1824; post (Box McComb Box 22)
- City Hall Records "3.d Bill Copy of a Bill for Marble for the New City Hall sent to Johnson &. Stevens at West Stockbridge on 23d July 1804 Am.t of Bill 3171'-, 1804; July 23 (Box McComb Box 22)
- City Hall Records "CHRONOLOGY OF EVENTS IN THE BUILDING OF THE CITY HALL": UL-UR, 1801-1956 (Box McComb Box 22)
- City Hall: attrib. Rear Elevation: attrib., [1804] (Box McComb Drawer 13, Item CH389)
- City Hotel ink, LC: "Broad-Way - 100"4-", [1792] (Box McComb Box 19, Item 396)
- City Hotel ink, LC: "Second Floor", [1792] (Box McComb Box 19, Item 397)
- Coach house/ stable [attrib] (Box McComb box 1, Item 010b)
- Coles, John B. Esquire Residence ink, MC-ML: "Second and third Floors of a House disign'd for John B. Coles Esqr" (Box McComb box 6, Item 101)
- Coles, John B. Esquire Residence ink, UC-LC: "Basement & First Story of a House disign'd for John B. Coles Esquire" (Box McComb box 6, Item 100)
- Coles, John B. Esquire Residence ink, LL-LC: "Elevation of a House disign'd for John B. Coles Esquire on White Hall Street" (Box McComb box 6, Item 102a recto)
- Column volute, attrib. (Box McComb Box 20, Item 427 verso)
- Columns, paired and pier design Paired columns; rusticated pier: attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 348)
- Construction details, attributed ink, UL-UR: "a Trussed Girder with the Truss mortised in with an Iron bolt and Screw Iron Plates at the ends of the Trusses" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 417)
- Construction details, attributed (Box McComb Box 20, Item 418)
- Cornice moldings, attrib. pencil, UL-UR: "St Pauls NYC gallery front" (Box McComb Box 21, Item 456 bis)
- Cornices ink, ML: "Cornice at Large" (Box McComb Box 17, Item 338)
- Cornices, attached columns Designs for mantelpieces. Cf. Adam designs: attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 334)
- Cornices, Doorways - 3 Detail of a column from a fireplace of Adam designs.: attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 335)
- Country house, unidentified Front Elevation: attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 407)
- Croton Aqueduct "Abstract of Corporation Ordinances and Rules adopted by the Croton Aqueduct Department,...", January 15, 1851 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 339 (2))
- Design for a Gazebo. [attrib in pencil on secondary support LC, by S. D. Stillman, 1955] (Box McComb box 1, Item 15)
- Design for ceiling, eagle and garlands, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 311)
- Detail Study of a furnace for heating, attrib. (Box McComb Box 21, Item 432)
- Distillery ink, ML-MC: "Plan of a distiliry for Martin Madan Esq" (Box McComb Box 13, Item 225)
- Dominic Lynch House ink, LL-LR: "Principal floor of Dom.k Lynch's House - at West Chester" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 236)
- Dominic Lynch House (Box McComb Box 14, Item 238)
- Dominic Lynch House ink, LC-LR: "Basement floor of Dominic Lynches House at West Chester" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 237)
- Door sketch, attrib. Arched doorway with keystone: attrib. (Box McComb Box 20, Item 424 verso)
- Doors Door frames - 4 designs: attributed, 1799 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 379)
- Doors Door openings with Gibbsian reveals: attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 380)
- Doorway designs (3), attrib. (Box McComb Box 17, Item 336)
- Doorways - 2, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 310)
- Duane Street Church ink, LC: "duane street" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 263)
- E. Leavenworths and Wm. Coits House ink, LL-LC: "Plan of W.m Coits House, Brooklyn" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 269b 1/2 verso)
- Ear Trumpet, attributed (Box McComb Box 12, Item 205b verso)
- Educational institution (Box McComb box 6, Item 112)
- Educational institution verso, ink, UC-UR: "The written plan approved & adopted by the Board of Trustees March 3d 1808 Wm. P. Deare Att.", 1808, ink verso UC-UR (Box McComb box 6, Item 111)
- Educational institution (Box McComb box 6, Item 113)
- Eldridge St. No. 48, Map verso, ink, UC: "Map of Ground in Eldridge St No 48", 1825, April 15 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 346)